<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Schemata on Galant Schemata</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/</link><description>Recent content in Schemata on Galant Schemata</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do-Re-Mi</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/do-re-mi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/do-re-mi/</guid><description>Examples The Do-Re-Mi in which both ➆ and ➄ occur in the second event.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 2, mvt. 3, Minuetto, m. 1 (London, 1766) The Do-Re-Mi with an extended first stage.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 3, mvt. 1, Allegro, m. 1 (London, 1766)</description></item><item><title>Fenaroli</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/fenaroli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/fenaroli/</guid><description>Variants The full Durante countermelody is ➎–➍–➌–➊–➐–➎–➊–➌, with two tones for each of the four tones ➆–➀–➁–➂. Either voice may be placed in the bass. (Gjerdingen 2007, 462)
The following examples feature the countermelody reduced to its bare essentials, ➍–➌–➐–➊, and set in the bass. They resemble Ex. 16.10 in Music in the Galant Style (Gjerdingen 2007, 232).
A repeated, pre-cadential Fenaroli.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 1, mvt. 1, Allegretto, m.</description></item><item><title>Prinner</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/prinner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/prinner/</guid><description>Examples The Prinner as a riposte to a Romanesca with a stepwise bass. Arguably the first measure of the Prinner constitutes the third measure of the Romanesca and thus the schemata overlap.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 3, mvt. 2, Allegretto, m. 33 (London, 1766) The Prinner as riposte to a Romanesca in the galant style. The D-sharp in the second beat of the Prinner is likely an error in the original score (Welcker 1765, 13); Henle uses a D-natural with an editorial accidental (Heinemann 1981, 18) and Ex.</description></item><item><title>Quiescenza</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/quiescenza/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/quiescenza/</guid><description>Examples The Quiescenza at the start of the second section of a movement in binary form. This schema is repeated in the score and features a pedal point on ➀. The third event includes the unstable sonority ♮7/2.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 1, mvt. 2, Tempo di Minuetto, m. 30 (London, 1766) The Quiescenza at the end of a section. The arpeggi reiterate ➀.
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no.</description></item><item><title>Romanesca</title><link>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/romanesca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpetchler.github.io/galant-schemata/schemata/romanesca/</guid><description>Examples A Romanesca in the galant style with a Prinner riposte. See also Ex. 2.23 in Music in the Galant Style (Gjerdingen 2007, 41).
J. C. Bach, Opus 5, no. 3, mvt. 1, Allegro, m. 63 (London, 1766) Repeated Romanescas in the galant style.
J. C. Bach, Opus 17, no. 1, mvt. 1, Allegro, m. 7 (Paris, 1773–74) Variants A leaping type, in which the bass alternately leaps down a fourth and steps up a second, all with 5/3 sonorities (the fourth of which was minor).</description></item></channel></rss>